大家好，我是Sean
所以今天
我们将介绍爱马仕智能体harness(马具)
和它的循环工程系统
这是最受欢迎的harness之一
现在的Agent系统，也是开源项目
如果你查看他们的GitHub
他们拥有超过20万个星星
在很短的时间内
所以它基本上是一个自我改进的AI智能体
由一个名为Nous Research的研究实验室构建
它具有内置学习循环
从经验中创造自己的技能
而不是你告诉AI
像CLAUDE CODE一样制作技能
同时，它也会随着时间的推移而不断改进
当你持续使用它时，因为它不断地
在本地机器中存储知识
就像在你的MacBook中一样
但无论如何，这就是所有的热词
我们将进入Hermes智能体系统设计
如常
我们也将通过他们的桌面应用程序进行测试
给你一个快速示例
它就像一个CLAUDE代码，对吧
可以看到他在思考
然后他就像皮卡丘一样回答我
我说，“Pikapi，就在我的目录里待着”
因为它是
就是一个在我的本地机器文件中生活的机器人
今天要修复什么建筑？
同时，你也可以通过WhatsApp与其互动
然后就说
早上好
有点慢
我用的是谷歌Gemini3.1模型
花了大约五秒
现在
它基本就是通过WhatsApp来获取信息
接收来自我的WhatsApp账户的信息
所以我可以直接发短信给它，让它帮我完成任务
并说“皮卡皮卡”
早上好
你可能已经意识到了
我稍微改变了他的性格
还有更多有趣的东西我可以给你看
对于那些看过我之前视频的人
智能体harness和循环工程和记忆系统
你可能会发现这个图表有些相似
这是上一幅图的样子
再看一下Hermes Agent的harness
我增加了一些信息
尤其是Hermes harness与普通harness的区别
与通用的 harness 系统相比
我用红色标出了差异
我们将一步步进行
此外，我准备了一些测试示例来涵盖 harness
记忆技能
循环、沟通界面和llm Ops或eval
因为很多人问我是否能
实现一些实例
所以，我们来了
不拖泥带水，直接进入主题
好，首先
让我们来看看Hermes harness 的基础
Agent 是一个在本地机器上运行的调度器
您可以使用本地命令行
Docker SSH 或虚拟 VPS
与Hermes智能体的互动主要有两种方式
一种方式是使用你喜欢的通讯应用
在我的例子中，我使用了WhatsApp
或者你也可以直接使用他们的桌面应用
和Hermes智能体商一起
您可以访问Hermes官方网站
爱马仕-智能体-nous研究com，然后
点击下载Mac OS
或者你可以点击“Windows”
这里使用命令行安装它
本质上仍然是一个聊天机器人，就像CLAUDE CODE一样
并向其中一个提问
通信应用程序
或者桌面版本与Open Claw非常相似
你可以使用WhatsApp来控制它
用户发送指令后，
用户会收到当前聊天记录
系统的问题
将被输入到工作记忆中
然后这个LLM
智能体本质上是Hermes智能体
这将回答你的问题
这里会使用循环工程
调用仅在Hermes上的一些工具
最后，当我完成任务后
将结束循环，然后回复用户
直接发送一个问题
在整个短暂的代理运行过程中
然后获取用户回复
就像我的Hermes像皮卡丘一样迎接我
顺便问一下，这是怎么发生的？
我现在就给你看
系统提示给Hermes的是有趣的
它叫做SOUL.MD
我真的喜欢他们给它起的名字，写着"soul"
如果你来到右侧，
你可以看到有一个小文件栏
这是你的本地文件
你可以去查找，会发现有一个名为Hermes的文件夹
我们打开它，然后向下滑动
你会看到一个名为SOUL.MD的文件
我们会点击它
你可以自己编辑这个，对吧？
但既然我已经编辑过了
编辑完任何内容后，只需点击保存
我说它像图片那样说话
每一条回复都以“pika pika pika pi”开头和结束
如果你很兴奋，说皮卡皮, 加上闪电表情
如果你感到悲伤，就安静地说“pika”
我很确定你可以做类似的事情
在CLAUDE CODE中
类似的内容将在自定义通用中
你可以看到有一条给Claude的指示
你可以告诉克劳德做某些事
并不要做某些事情
它基本上就是系统提示
在整个智能体中使用
马具
如果你没有看我的上一视频关于harness(马具)
在循环工程的 harness 中，基本就是
一套工具让你控制
对这匹非常强大的马
这就是LLM本身
在我们的例子中，我们使用的LLM是双子座
因为我有了Google的信用
我不想浪费我的Anthropic积分
请自由使用Anthropic
这是马的智能体
而马具就是这个整体
就像你骑在马鞍上的马鞍一样
确保马不跑掉
随机，并按照工具使用
正确方向上移动
harness(马具)是一个模糊的概念
别胡思乱想，其实没什么复杂
这只是一个热门词
我们继续构建这一套harness
对Hermes来说，就在这里
但我要展示的是一个循环的概念
概念“循环”在这些年里非常流行
很多人都在构建智能体
你不希望总是告诉智能体什么要做
你希望智能体能推理出
什么问题应该发送？
什么工具它应该调用？
让我们看看什么工具
Hermes的智能体实际上需要启用这个循环
工程
我们将简要介绍这一话题
然后我会给你一些实例
首先，
Hermes的智能体拥有一组工具
包括终端
浏览器，好的
你可以使用你的笔记本电脑的终端
你可以启动浏览器，它可以分配任务
这意味着它可以生成一些子智能体
比如说，为了实现这个目标，我们需要一些工具
你可以让它生成一个智能体
它将调用您的CLAUDE CODE
CLI为您编写代码
如果任务主要是修复一些问题，我可能会去看一下
然后它可以安排定时任务
一个Cron job 可以定时执行某项任务
会在特定时间发生
不需要人为干预，就能完成cron job
现在就试试在Hermes智能体
我可以说，“帮我设置一个Cron Job”
每分钟告诉我一个宝可梦笑话
下10分钟，好的
我就直接发送这个
我还会把这个发送给我们的Hermes智能体
WhatsApp界面也可以，我就直接说
告诉我一个开发者笑话
它很快就称之为cron作业，上面写着
重复10次，下10分钟
因为它在终端UI上显示挂起
它无法打印，所以我需要问它
我只是问，第一段笑话是什么
在WhatsApp上，你也能看到它已经安排好了
Cron就是它
幽默机已启动并计划好了
我已经设置了一个cron作业来给你发一个新笑话
下10分钟每分钟
大约一分钟后，你将收到第一条
我们来看看吧，好吗？
为什么杰尼龟要穿越海洋
为了得到另一个潮汐。皮卡皮卡
好的，这就是cron的工作
它也能进行技能管理
它也可以连接到MCP
用户提问的问题决定了结果
智能体将利用这些工具
完成后，它会回复你
好的，我们刚刚看到的例子是cron作业
稍后我还会给你展示更多例子
让我们测试一些 harness 和 loop 示例
第一个是
使用终端工具查找我当前的操作系统版本
读我最近十行的Shell历史
让我们来做
开始新的会话
我就会问它这个问题
你可以看到，我在本地机器上运行了这个
然后它发现我在Mac OS 26.5上
最后十行我用在了显示中
历史基本是文本
获取状态，获取状态
查看状态，我总是喜欢检查它
并且这里
发生的是，它运行了这个智能体程序
然后它调用了终端来完成任务
这是检查我在哪个系统上
这是一个非常简单的例子
但你可以做更多疯狂的事情
可以让它使用本地机器
让你的终端帮你完成任务
如果你使用的是CLAUDE CODE
你对这个已经非常熟悉了，好吗？
没什么特别的
我只是给你展示一个例子
这是一个马具
并且有一个循环，因为我获取它后就会出现
它会停止，告诉我并回复我
让我们也看看cron作业
你可以看到他们已经给我发了两个笑话
为什么Java开发者戴眼镜？
因为他们看不到锐利的pika pika
我要告诉你一个UDP笑话
但我完全没有
没有保证你能得到它
我不管他们是否回应
皮卡，这个我没懂
再给个例子
访问YouTube频道Sean's AI Stories
标题加观看次数 我的上一视频
为本视频创建新标题
我正在录制
所以我们在这里基本要求你使用浏览器
好的，你可以看到它开始搜索了
所有这些东西都已经存在于CLAUDE CODE上
我只是从系统设计角度来解释
给你示例，好吗？
然后也
我将向您展示两者之间的区别
Hermes和CLAUDE CODE之间的区别
请耐心等待
好的，我需要运行一个Python脚本
所以你可以看到，也可以使用一些点击工具
哦，出了个错误
网站有误
试试这个新的
它在这里节省了一些内存
好的，显示了用户资料更新
这是我稍后会提到的
但是，剧透
Hermes Agent会自动保存Agent的记忆
基本也在本地文件中
如果你在Hermes文件夹中来这里
如果你在记忆中往下滚动
你可以看到有一个记忆点MD
如果我们双击，它将存储在YouTube中
油管小爬虫技巧
因为他发现了错误，所以
所以它通过记忆自我更新了
这是这个harness的自我迭代过程
好的，它读取了我的之前的YouTube标题
发现我有这条视频
这条视频有十万人观看
现在我正在录制新视频
给了我一些新标题
这里发生的是用户
我是通过桌面问了这个问题
然后它进行了一次智能体运行
然后我正在使用的是这个智能体的Gemini harness
主要是调用浏览器，就在这里
搜索我的YouTube频道
然后它回应说，“嘿”
我没找到任何东西，所以它基本就停止了
有一个末端循环护栏
护栏停下来说
我没找到任何东西，所以意识到，好吧
上一个网页错误
所以我重新输入了，嗯
再次调用浏览器
它也被称为终端运行Python
脚本
因为他需要完成一些任务
最终，它返回了答案
有一个机制表示“好的”
结束循环
不再调用工具，直接发送答案
这是两个快速示例，说明了什么是“ harness”
循环工程是什么
你看，你每天都在使用它
没什么特别的
所以不要感到困惑
下次听到这些术语时
这只是一个热门词
刚才发生的就是这个记忆点MD
我们看到的关于YouTube的记忆
在或在智能体运行期间，Hermes Agent
它将开始构建自己的技能
内存和内存的MD
是否输入到程序记忆中取决
或者是输入到语义记忆中
我们需要在这儿加一个箭头
简而言之，Hermes智能体的工作方式是
它会存储自己的技能和记忆
完全本地
没有任何东西存储在云端
它有自己的自我改进循环
每次
当他们意识到某事是错误时
他们应该从中学习或这是重复的任务
它将开始总结
好的
以下是一些我应该知道的新记忆
为了更好地为用户服务
它开始将这些文件保存到
这两个部分是记忆系统
第一种叫做过程记忆
它基本上是你的行为方式
马智能体应该如何行动
通常，它会在一个名为Hermes的目录中保存
技能 熟练的 IMD Hermes
技能
这些中的任何一个都可以
自主AI智能体CLAUDE CODE
有一个技能用于
Hermes Agent将如何在这里使用CLAUDE CODE
所以它基本上将任何编码委托给CLAUDE CODE
CLI显示你应该怎么做
例如安装CLAUDE运行它
并进行认证等操作
我们刚刚看到的就是记忆
记忆点md保存的是语义记忆
这些是一些持久的事实
或与用户资料相关的事物
所以，如果用户有习惯，
或者有一些重要的事实或信息
记得
然后它会被保存在memory.md
有趣的是，对于Hermes来说
而不是做嵌入式
实际上，它只是使用纯文本
好的，它使用了顶级关键字
而不是做嵌入或RAG系统
这非常有趣，因为我不太确定为什么
但它只是处理文本
记住，我们说智能体运行是一瞬间的
现在
将工作记忆输入到智能体中
对于所有循环工程
包括过程记忆
语义记忆，之后我们将讨论 Episodic 记忆
这将成为一个更完整的记忆系统
这将输入到智能体运行中
这使得 harness 更加优雅
我们还没有提到的第三支柱是
它被称为 Episodic 记忆
它基本上是聊天记录或一些有日期的事件
它可以是RAG或SQL
进入工作记忆中
每次智能体运行后
信息将流入 Episodic 记忆
不同的是，在Hermes中，
数据不保存在云端
它在一个名为“statedotb”的地方被封存
再回到右侧栏上
如果我们再次打开爱马仕文件夹，向下滚动
最后，你可以看到有一个状态点DB
我可以点击预览
无论如何
这基本上是一个数据库
这将包含所有聊天记录中的信息
但也随着时间的推移
它将开始合并一些聊天记录
使用Hermes辅助模型
哪个更便宜？
不重要的模型用于进行这项摘要任务
让它将一些事实浓缩为
我们称之为语义记忆
或者说，记忆是在不断地被消磨
所以你可以看到
这套 harness 正在自我改进
自律状态
这真的很酷
我不
这个图表比平常更复杂
我觉得这应该是一个完整的总结
关于Hermes智能体的工作方式
让我们再看几个例子
让我们测试一些关于记忆的内容
保存到记忆中
我最喜欢的测试框架是Pytest
这是一个明确的节省
对，它更新了内存文件
所以，如果我们去记忆中
你可以看到一个额外的块
用户最喜欢的测试框架是Pytest
这是一个明确的请求，源自入口
这里是用的工具基本上是
让我们更新这里的记忆吧
查找我们的过去会话
我对你说过的第一句话是什么？
现在在循环使用搜索工具
工程迭代
我说的第一句话是
你能做什么，Hermes？你有什么特别之处？
让我们再确认一下是否正确
但它失败了，因为当时我无法登录
所以发生的是
我通过界面提出了问题
它通过提示，并在工作记忆中
因为我们问了
因此，它从 Episodic Memory 中获取了信息
来自state. db
它将记忆回传给了智能体
智能体说：“哦，好的”
这就是你说的
让我们尝试一个技能相关的例子
这就是程序式记忆
所以我们要创建一个技能，名为视频准备
这说明了我如何格式化我的视频脚本
英语中的专业术语解释在线
没有m连字号，结尾为
你可以构建任何事物，你可以学习任何事物
这是直接让系统去更新Skills技能文件
它使用了技能管理工具
记住在循环工程中
有一个工具叫技能管理
这就是他做的和说的
皮卡皮，我成功创建了视频预备技能
让我们再了解一下，Hermes技能
媒体视频预备，双击
他为我创建了这个技能
它说没有“——”的英语
定义俚语，在语境中捕捉短语
你可以构建任何东西，也可以学习任何有用的技能
我们可以进一步测试循环
我们可以说，使用委托任务来生成两个子智能体
一个正在研究LM Eval Harness
另一个正在研究VLM架构
智能体正在调用工具，被称为委托任务
并成功孵化了两个后台智能体
你可以看到它现在正在处理
他们正在并行工作
酷
最后将结果返回给我
你可以看到
它为我生成了一些子智能体来完成任务
并行
我们已经尝试过cron作业
下一个是 启动子智能体
它使用CLAUDE CLI，这是我最喜欢的
这是我最喜欢的
生成一个使用克劳德的子智能体
CLI 在无头模式下
基本使用Claud构建Python脚本
获取前五条黑客新闻
标记并验证运行
是的，它首先将任务委托给了克劳德
为什么，因为他在使用这个尺度
记得我们在自主AI智能体中阅读了这个技能
克劳德，你应该学习这个技能
这有帮助吗？
请告诉我这是否有帮助
意思是，我想给你更多例子
在演示中，让它更具具体感
因为
很多人问我关于实现的问题
从我的之前的视频
我觉得Hermes是个很好的例子
好的，它为我创建了这个呃代码，并使用了CLAUDE
它创建了fetch_hn.py
我只说，运行脚本后给我看结果
是的，所以
这是 Hacker News 上的前五大黑客新闻故事
来检查一下，看看是否有问题
记得发生了什么事
我们从网关发送了问题
它通过智能体运行
LLM基本上赶上了名为委托任务的工具
DelegatTask 将任务委托给子智能体
子智能体正在运行CLAUDE CODE
CLAUDE CODE编写了该脚本并将其发送回
然后这个智能体再次运行了脚本
然后我们得到结果
这是编程中的硬盘驱动器
在整个过程中
我不认为它是自发的
还没有自学技能
它只触发了记忆学习
我只是想问清楚
你自己保存了哪些技能？
或者你只是保存了记忆吗？
哦，是的
但我们创造了它，创造了这个技能
你没有自发意识到需要保存技能
应主动提供保存技能的机会
在艰难的迭代任务后
有5次或更多的工具调用
到目前为止，我们还没有做过难的事情
我们可以测试门户
我可以概括今天我们做了什么
嗯，这个cron作业失败了
它没告诉我十个笑话
只告诉我了两个
其他的笑话是什么？
别骗我
因为也许你只是刚刚创建的
如果你在观看的是Hermes团队
你的cron作业没有更新它
除非我要求结果
所以可能你们可以解决这个问题
alright
让我们继续并总结今天所做的工作
因为在这个聊天中
它不知道这里的其他内容
让我们看看它是否调用了实际的
记得我们说过的“待定”吧
记忆MD和技能MD
好的，她知道了，没问题
它说的是即时笑话系统
检查操作系统版本，这就是我们做的
是的，YouTube的人气
我们做了那个黑客新闻
好的，很好
这里的WhatsApp只是一个界面
它正在与Hermes Agent Desktop做同样的事情
这很酷，对吧？
这类似于Open Claw，但我想说的是，
但每次都一样
当我感到
我只需拥有一个个人助手
方便在我的WhatsApp上
这真的很酷
想象一下，如果我在虚拟机上运行这个
它永不停止运行
我可以直接问WhatsApp发生了什么
它会对我说“哦”
我完全忘了
你应该通过输入"Hermes WhatsApp"来设置WhatsApp
然后按照说明设置即可
应该很简单
最后但同样重要的是，评估系统在哪里
我们的LLM Ops在哪里
记得在原始图表中
我们右手边有一个蓝色的盒子，叫做LLM Ops
所以很不幸爱马仕
根据我目前的研究
我不认为它有LLM Ops或评估系统
你可能需要自己构建它
但它可以追踪运行
有一个名为轨迹导出和日志的功能
它基本就是记录整个过程
但没有评估
如果你看了我们之前的视频
Evo基本上是你可以使用像LangSmith这样的工具
LangFuse
以及所有这些可以跟踪的东西
整个智能体运行
以及一些发生的事件，如工具调用
你调用了多少次LLM
你使用了一些更便宜的模型吗？
将事情概括到你的语义记忆中
遗憾的是，Hermes不提供这样的功能
我想知道为什么
可能是因为它是本地系统
所以你可以自己进行个性化定制
它在Hermes下
你可以点击日志查看
在这里可以看到所有日志，也可以看到错误
可以看到智能体运行的网关
logs 到 Gateway 是入口点
这是WhatsApp还是桌面应用？
我希望这对你有所帮助
我觉得有
我们今天所覆盖的工作量很大
这正是CLAUDE CODE已经可以做到的
或者小龙虾，它就可以做了
我觉得爱马仕的特别之处
至少与CLAUDE CODE相比
它是通过本地自动更新所有这些东西的
可能这对隐私有好处
因为我不明白为什么
我们不应该将其保存在云端
除此之外，其他一切应该非常相似
对，它运行循环
每次当智能体需要完成某项任务时
呼叫这些所有的小工具
你甚至可以安排一个cron任务
然后是记忆
技能会自动更新
存储在程序内存中
语义记忆
并将状态数据保存到 Episodic 中
记忆
所以我认为这是一个标准的 harness
对于一个智能体实现
没什么特别复杂的，但我相信他们做了大量工作
但我觉得这是一个很好的示例，说明建构者应该如何构建
现在应该是产品开发的时候
因为这正在成为标准，对吧？
每一个
AI 智能体工具应该自我改进
并且自我演化
并根据用户请求
你可以选择本地存储
可以放在云端
这取决于你
我觉得技能和记忆是最重要的
积聚可能是最
这其中最宝贵的东西
因为用户逐渐被锁定在其中
它记得我是谁
这就是为什么
近来，我不再使用其他AI了
我只用了克劳德
对我的语义记忆
我的公司信息Automanus.io
以及我制作YouTube视频的风格
是的，我觉得这是个不错的框架
你们应该试试
真的很有趣
好的，希望这视频对你有所帮助
如果有问题，请问
请在下面留言
如果你喜欢的话
请点赞并订阅
请告诉我你还想看什么
下次见，谢谢
hi everyone this is Sean
so today
we're gonna walk through Hermes Agent Harness
and its loop engineering system
this is one of the most popular harness
agent system right now and it's an open source project
if you check their Github
they've got more than 200,000 stars
in a very short period of time
so it's basically a self improving AI agent
built by this research lab called Nous Research
and it's a built in learning loop
creates its own skills from experience
instead of you telling the AI
like CLAUDE CODE to make skills
and then it also improves over time
when you keep using it because it persistently
stores knowledge in your local machine
like in your MacBook
but anyways this is all the buzzwords
we're gonna jump into this Hermes agent system design
like usual
we're gonna test it as well using their desktop app
just give you a quick example
it's like a CLAUDE CODE right
you can see that he was thinking
and then he answered me in like a Pikachu style
he said pikapi just hang out in the my directory
because it's
literally a bot living in my local machine files
whatever building fixing today
and also you can interact with it on WhatsApp
and then just say
good morning
it's a little bit slow
I'm using a Gemini 3.1 model for this
it took like a good five seconds
and now
it's basically just using WhatsApp as the gateway to
receive information from my WhatsApp account
so I can just text it and ask it to do things for me
and say Pika P
good morning
you probably realized that
I've changed his personality a little bit
and there are more interesting things I can show you
for those who have watched my previous video on
agent harness and loop engineering and memory system
you might realize that this chart is somewhat similar
this is what the previous chart looks like
and now if we look at harness for Hermes Agent again
I added a bit more information
especially the difference between the Hermes harness
versus a generic harness system
I marked the differences in red
so we're gonna walk through this step by step
also I prepared some testing examples to cover harness
memory skills
loop, gateway, and llm Ops or eval
because a lot of people were asking me if I could
implement some real examples
so here we are
without further do let's jump right in
okay so firstly
let's look at the foundation of Hermes Harness
Agent is a harness that runs on your local machine
you can use either local command lines
Docker SSH or a virtual VPS
there are two main ways to interact with Hermes Agent
one is using your favourite communication apps
and in my case I used WhatsApp
or you can just use your desktop app
with the Hermes Agent
so you can come to Hermes official website
Hermes dash agent dot nous research com and just
click on download for Mac OS
or you can click on Windows
over here to use the command line to install it
essentially still a chat bot just like CLAUDE CODE
and you ask the question to either
the communication app
or the desktop version is very similar to Open Claw
where you can use WhatsApp to control it
so after user send the prompt
the user prompt with the current chat history
and the system prompt
will be fed into a working memory
and then this LLM
agent is basically the Hermes agent
that will be answering your question
and it will be using a loop engineering over here
to call up some tools that are only on Hermes
and eventually after I finish the task
it's gonna end the loop and then send the user a reply
just literally sending a question
throughout this entire ephemeral agent run
and then get the user reply
just like my hermits was greeting me like a Pikachu
and by the way how did this happen right
I'll show you right now
so the system prompt for Hermes is interesting
it's called SOUL.MD
I really like how they named it it says soul
if you come to the right hand side
you can see there's a little file bar
and this is your local files
and you can go find out there's a dot Hermes folder
and we open that and if we scroll down
you will see there is a file called SOUL.MD
that we'll click on that
and you can edit this yourself right
but since I've already edited it
after you edit anything you can just click on save
I basically say you talk like Pikachu
every reply starts at end with pika pika pika pi
if you are excited say pikapi with the lightning
if you're sad say quiet pika
I'm pretty sure you can do something similar
in CLAUDE CODE for this
in CLAUDE CODE
something similar will be in Customize General
and you can see there's an instruction for Claude
you can tell Claude to do certain things
and not to do certain things
it's basically the system prompt
used across the entire agent
harness
if you didn't watch my previous video on harness
and loop engineering harness is basically
a set of tools that allows you to control
over this really powerful horse
which is the LLM itself
in our case the LLM we're using is Gemini
because I've got the Google credits
I don't want to burn my anthropic credits
but feel free to use anthropic
this is the this is the agent of the the horse
and the harness is this entire thing
it's like a horse harness that you ride on
and you make sure that the horse is not going anywhere
random and it's using the tools accordingly
to move in the right direction
harness is a very vague concept
just don't fantasize it it's nothing complicated
it's just a buzzword
and we're gonna continue to build up this harness
right here for Hermes
but what I'm gonna show you is what a loop is
the concept loop got really popular because these days
people build a lot of agents
you don't want to always tell the agent what to do
you want the agent to figure out
what kind of problem you should send
what kind of tools you should call
let's take a look at what tools
Hermes agent actually have to enable this loop
engineering
we're gonna cover this briefly
and then I'll show you real examples
so first of all
the agent of Hermes is having a set of tools
that include the terminal
the browser okay
you can use your laptop's terminal
you can start a browser you can delegate task
which means that you can spawn up some sub agents
for you for example
you can ask it to spawn up an agent
which will call your CLAUDE CODE
CLI to write code for you
if the task is basically fixing some bugs on my Github
and then it can schedule a Cron job
a Cron job is basically it can schedule something
that will happen at a certain time
you don't need human intervention to do it for cron job
let's just try it right now in hermesation
I can say help me set up a cron job
that will tell me a Pokemon joke every minute
in the next 10 minutes okay
I'm just gonna send this
and also I'm gonna send this to our Hermes Agent
WhatsApp interface too and instead I'll just say
tell me a developer joke every
it just quickly called this a cron job and it says
repeats 10 times for the next 10 minutes
because it says it's hanging in the terminal UI
it won't be able to print it so I need to ask it
I just ask like what's the first joke
and you can see on WhatsApp it also got scheduled
the Cron is it
the joke machine is powered and scheduled
I've set up a cron job to send you a fresh joke
every minute in the next 10 minutes
you should receive the first one in about a minute
we'll see about that okay
and why did the squirtle cross the ocean
to get the other tide. pika pika
OK so that was cron job
it can do skill management as well
it can connect to MCPs as well
it depends on the question that the user asks
the agent will just leverage these tools
until it's done and then it will send a reply to you
okay the example we just saw was cron job
I'm gonna show you some more examples later too
let's test a few harness and loop examples
the first one is
use a terminal tool to find out what OS version I'm on
and read the last 10 lines of my shell history
let's do that
let's start a new session
just gonna ask this exact question to it
so you can see it ran this on my local machine
and then it figured out that I'm on Mac OS 26.5
and the last 10 lines I used in shell
history is basically text
get status get status
get status I always like to check get status
and here
what happened was that it ran through this agent run
and then it called the terminal to do the task for me
which is checking what system I'm on
this is a very simple example
but you can do more crazy things
you can ask it to use the local machine
terminal to do things for you
if you're using CLAUDE CODE
you're you're very familiar with this already alright
there's nothing special about it
I'm just showing you the example
that this is a harness
and there's a loop because after I fetched it
it will stop and tell me and reply to me
let's look at the cron job as well
you can see they send me two jokes already
why do Java developers wear glasses
because they don't see sharp pika pika
I would tell you a UDP joke
but I have absolutely
no guarantee that you would get it
I'm not going to wait for acknowledgement anyways
pika okay this one I didn't get it
so one more example
browse to YouTube channel Sean's AI Stories
title plus views my last videos
create new video titles for this current video
I am filming
so here we're asking you to use the browser basically
okay you can see that it started doing the searching
all these things already exist on CLAUDE CODE
I'm just explaining it from a system design perspective
and showing you examples okay
and then also
I will show you what's the difference between
Hermes and CLAUDE CODE
so please bear with me
alright so I need to run a python script
so you can see also use some clicking tools
oh there's an error
the website was wrong
try this new one
it saved a little memory here
okay it said user profile updated
this is something I'm gonna cover in a bit
but spoil alert
Hermes Agent will save Agent Memories by itself
it's basically in your local files too
if you come here within the Hermes folder
if you scroll down in memories
you can see there's a memory dot MD
if we double click on that it's stored YouTube here
YouTube scraping quirk
so because he realized that it had a mistake
so it updated itself with the memory
this is a self iterating process of this harness
good so it read my previous YouTube titles
it realized that I've got this video
that's got 100,000 views
and since I'm filming a new video now
it gave me some new titles
so what happened here was the user
which is me who asked the question through the desktop
and then it went through this agent run
and then this agent harness Gemini that I'm using
I was basically using calling the browser right here
to search up my YouTube channel
and then it came back and said hey
I didn't find anything so uh it basically stopped
there's an end loop guardrail
the guardrail stopped and said
I didn't find anything so I realized that OK
the previous URL was wrong
so I input it again uh
it called the browser again
and it also called the terminal to run some Python
script
and because it needed to do some task
and eventually came back with the answer
there's a mechanism that says OK
end the loop
no more tool calls and send the answer
these are two quick examples of what a harness
loop engineering is
you see you're already using it every single day
it's nothing fancy
so don't get overwhelmed
next time when you hear these terms
it's just a buzzword
so what happened just now was this memory dot MD
that we saw regarding YouTube memory
Hermes Agent after or during the agent run
it's gonna start to create its own skill
AMD and memory AMD
depending on if it's feeding into the procedure memory
or if it's feeding into the semantic memory
and we should add one more arrow here basically
so essentially the way that Hermes Agent works
is that it's storing its own skills and memories
completely locally
nothing is stored on the cloud
it has its own self improving loop
every time
when they realize that something is a mistake
they should learn from or it's a repeated task
it will start to summarize
OK
here are some new memories I should know for the future
in order to serve this user well
it started to save these files into
these two chunks of memory system
the first one is called Procedure Memory
it's basically how you act
how the horse agent should be acting
and it's usually saved in this directory called Hermes
Skills Skilled IMD Hermes
Skills
and any of these OK
autonomous AI agent CLAUDE CODE
there's a skill for
how Hermes Agent will use CLAUDE CODE here
so it will basically delegate any coding to CLAUDE CODE
CLI shows exactly how you should do it
like install CLAUDE run it
and do the authentication and all these kind of things
and then what we just saw earlier was memories
the memory dot m d is saving the semantic memory
which are some durable facts
or things related to the user profile
so if the user has a habit
or has some important facts or information
you should remember
then it will be saved in the memory.md
and then what's interesting is that for Hermes
instead of doing the embeddings
it's actually just using plain text
okay it's using the top key keyword
instead of doing the embedding or the RAG system
it's very interesting because I'm not too sure why
but it's just doing text
so remember that we say the agent run is ephemeral
now
that with a working memory to be fed into the agent
for all the loop engineering
which includes procedural memory
semantic memory and later we'll cover episodic memory
this will become a more complete memory system
that will feed into the agent runs
which is making the harness more elegant
and the third pillar that we haven't covered
is called episodic memory
it's basically the chat history or some dated events
it can be RAG or SQL
into the working memory
after every agent run
the information will flow into the episodic memory
what's different in Hermes is that
the data is not saved in the cloud
it's saved in this place called state dot DB
again let's come back here on the right hand side bar
if we again open Hermes folder, scroll down
you can see at the end there's a state dot DB
and I can click on preview
anyway
this is basically a database
that will include all those info in your chat history
but also over time
it will start to consolidate some of those chats
using the Hermes auxiliary models
which are cheaper
non important models to do this summarization task
so that it will distill some facts into
what we call the semantic memory
or that memory DMD
so you can see
this harness is running really in a self improving
autonomous situation
which is really cool
I know
this chart is getting more complicated than usual
I feel like this should be a complete summary
for how the Hermes agent works
and let's go through a few more examples
let's test out some of the stuff for memories
save to memory
that my favorite testing framework is pytest
so this is an explicit saving
alright it updated the memory file
so if we go to memory
you can see one more block
which is user's favorite testing framework is pytest
that was an explicit ask from the gateway
the tool is basically
let's go update the memory over here
search our past sessions
what was the very first thing I ever say to you
now as using the searching tool in a loop
engineering iteration
say the first thing I say is
what can you do Hermes and what makes you special
let's double check that that's right
and it failed because I couldn't log in at that time
so what happened was
I asked the question through the interface
it went through the prompt and in the working memory
because we asked that
so it carried the information from episodic memory
from state.db
it returned the memory into the agent
the agent was like oh OK
this is what you said
let's try an example related to skills
which is procedural memory
so we're gonna say create a skill called video prep
that captures how I format my video scripts
spoken English define jargon on in line
no m dashes closes with
you can build anything you can learn anything
this is an explicit call to update the skills
it used the skill management tool
remember in the loop engineering
there's a tool called skill management
and this is what it did and say
Pika P I have successfully created the video prep skill
let's find out about it again Hermes Skills
Media Video Prep double click
you created this skill for me
it says no m dashes spoken English
define jargon in line catchphrase
you can build anything you can learn anything good
we can test the loop a little bit more
we can say use delegate task to spawn two sub agents
one is researching the LM eval harness
another one researching VLM architecture
the agent was calling the tool called Delegate Task
and successfully spawned two background agents
so you can see it's processing right now over here
they're working in parallel
cool
eventually return the results to me
so you can see that
it's spawned up some sub agents to do tasks for me
in parallel
we've already tried the cron job
and the next one is spawn sub agent
that uses CLAUDE CLI it's my favourite
so this is my favorite
spawn a sub agent that uses the clod
CLI in headless mode
basically using clod to build a Python script
fetching the top 5 hacker news stories
to markdown and verify runs
yep it firstly delegated task to Claude C L
I is using the skill you can see
remember we read the skill here in Autonomous AI Agent
Claude you should be reading this skill
is this helpful
let me know if this is helpful
I mean I was trying to show you more examples
in the walkthrough so that it feels more concrete
because
a lot of people were asking me for implementations
from my previous videos
and I feel like Hermes is a really good example
okay it created this uh code for me and used the CLAUDE
it created the fetch_hn.py
I just say show me the result after running the script
yep so
these are the top 5 Hacker News stories on Hacker News
let's come check it's correct
remember what happened
was that we sent the question from the Gateway
it went through the agent run and
the LLM basically caught up the tool called Delegate Task
Delegate Task delegated the task to sub agent
and the sub agent was running CLAUDE CODE
and CLAUDE CODE wrote that script and sent it back
and then this agent run the script again
and then we get the results
this was the harness and the loop engine
in this entire thing
I don't think it's self triggered
self learning skills yet
it only triggered learning the memory
I'm just gonna ask it explicitly
did you save any skills by yourself
or did you only save memory so far
oh yeah
but we created that but we created that skill
you did not self realize you need to save skill
hmm you should proactively offer to save a skill
after a difficult iterative task
with 5 or more tool calls
so far we haven't done anything difficult
so we can test the Gateway
I can summarize what we worked on today
hmm this cron job failed
it didn't tell me 10 jokes
it only took told me two
what were the rest of the jokes
don't lie to me
because maybe you just created it anyways
Hermes team if you're watching this
your cron job is not updating it
unless I ask for the results
so maybe this is something you guys can fix
alright
let's move on and summarize what we worked on today
because in this current chat
it doesn't know the rest of the stuff here
so let's see if it's calling the actual
remember we say state DB
memory MD and skills MD
good actually knows OK
it says jokes on demand system
check on the OS version which is what we did
YouTube stats yes
we did that hacker news
OK good
WhatsApp here is just a gateway as an interface
it's doing the same thing as the Hermes Agent Desktop
this is very cool this is
I mean this is similar to Open Claw
but still every time
when I feel
I can just have my personal assistant
handy on my WhatsApp
this is really cool
and imagine if I host this on a virtual machine
and it runs forever
I can just basically ask WhatsApp what's going on
and it's gonna reply to me ooh
I completely forgot
you should set up WhatsApp by typing in Hermes WhatsApp
and then just follow the instructions to set it up
should be straightforward
last but not least where is evaluation system
where is our LLM Ops
remember in our original chart
we had this blue box on the right hand side called LLM Ops
so unfortunately on Hermes
based on my current research
I don't think it has an LLM Ops or an eval system
you probably need to build it yourself
but it does trace the run
there's a thing called trajectory export and logs
and it's basically just logging the whole thing
but there's no eval
if you watch our previous video
the Evo is basically you can use tools like LangSmith
LangFuse
and all these things that can track
the entire agent run
and some events that happened like tool calls
how many times did you call LLMs
did you use some cheaper models
to summarize things into your semantic memory
unfortunately Hermes doesn't do that
I'm curious why
maybe because it's a local system
so you can just customize it yourself
it's under Hermes
you can click into logs
can see all the logs here can see the errors
can see the agent runs gateway
logs to Gateway is the entry point
which is WhatsApp or this desktop
I hope this was helpful
I think there's
quite a huge amount of work that we covered today
which are exactly what CLAUDE CODE can already do
or open claw can already do
I feel that what makes Hermes special
at least compared to CLAUDE CODE
is that it's self updating all these things locally
and maybe this is good for privacy reasons
because I don't see why
we should not save it on the cloud
other than that everything else should be very similar
right it runs the loop
every time when the agent needs to do some task
uh kind of call all these tools
and you can even schedule a cron job
and then the memories
and the skills are getting auto updated
into the procedure memory
semantic memory
and the state data will be saved into the episodic
memory
so I would say this is a pretty standard harness
for an agent implementation
nothing too fancy but I'm sure they did a ton of work
but I feel like this is a good example for how builder
these days should be building products
because this is becoming a standard right
every
AI agent tool should be self improving
and self evolving
and depend on the user request
you can either keep it local
you can keep it on the cloud
that's up to you
I feel like the skill and memory
accumulation is probably the
most valuable thing in this
because the user kind of just over time get locked in
and it remembers who I am
which is why
like recently I don't switch to other AI anymore
I just use Claude
it has a semantic memory about who I am
my company information Automanus.io
and what my style of building YouTube videos
but yeah I think it's a cool framework
you guys should try it out
it's really fun
cool I hope this video was helpful
and if you have any questions
please leave down a comment
and if you enjoyed it
please give me a like and subscribe
let me know what else you would like to watch
I will see you next time thanks